# ANDREA NARANJO LIMA

avnaranjolima@gmail.com | +593 987907458 | Guayaquil, Ecuador <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrea-naranjo-lima-192254184/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrea-naranjo-lima-192254184/</a>

#### **SUMMARY**

Software Engineer with 4+ years of experience in implementing top quality and user-friendly software applications. Developed front and back-end functionalities for B2B and B2C companies. Mentored peers to get acquainted with new solutions and led projects by creating and maintaining features to improve user experience and assure effectiveness. Involved in the design, built, update and launch of e-commerce, non-profit and companies websites and hybrid mobile apps.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Software Engineer, CTI - ESPOL

Jul 2024 - Present

- Maintenance of pages, forms, styles and flows in Government's platform.
- Implementation of new functionalities in website, always prioritizing effectiveness and efficiency.
- Find solutions to bugs or errors that the system might present, in front, backend and server side.

#### Software Engineer, Oceansecurity

Apr 2024 - Jun 2024

- Developed applications for administrative and operational staff.
- Evaluated and identified processes within the company and created solutions to increase efficiency and reduce work time.

#### Software Engineer, Expandya IT Services Provider

Dec 2021 - Mar 2024

- Led projects for USA clients.
- Implemented views, controllers and payment gateway for CMS solutions.
- Conducted deployments and code review and collaborated with crossfunctional teams to ensure the proposed solutions met clients' expectations.
- Updated automation jobs for database syncing and deployment.
- Set personal servers and mentored new members by introducing the projects, coding standards and required tools used by the whole team.

# Front End Developer, Viamática

Jun 2021 - Nov 2021

- Maintained and developed user interfaces and API calls for bank staff web application.
- Worked in new version of bank mobile app by creating new functions and components, improving UX and UI design.

#### Front End Developer, BioDynamicsTech

Jun 2020 - Aug 2020

 Implemented new features and components to manage shrimp pools, visualize data and download reports with graphical representation in hybrid mobile app.

#### Web Developer, Centro de Visión y Robótica ESPOL

Apr 2020 - Jul 2020

 Developed login and comments section, created templates and CSS styles for online repository to improve project management.

# **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor of Computer Science**

May 2014 - Sep 2020

Escuela Superior Politécnica del Litoral

#### **KEY SKILLS**

- JavaScript
- PHP
- Python
- CSS/Sass
- HTML5
- Drupal
- Wordpress
- JQuery
- Server Management

- PostgreSQL
- MongoDB
- Google Firebase
- Git
- Jira
- React
- VueJS
- Ionic
- NodeJS

# **SOFT SKILLS**

- Problem solving.
- Teamwork / Collaboration
- · Attention to details.
- Can adapt to work independently.
- Fluent in English and Spanish.
- Learning agility.
- Perform effectively in a deadline environment.
- Organizational and time management skills.
- Solid written & verbal communicator